Remember that in the timeline of communication system development,
your digestive system emerges very early.
The first movement in the communication system is a fluidic movement of the autocrine type.
In other words, I need to learn to know myself.
Once I know myself, I can exchange.
And only then can I digest.
Only after will the circulatory and endocrine connective system emerge.
Look at the system.
The endocrine system depends on my circulatory system.
First, I have my
enteric system appearing, and then only the parasympathetic and then the sympathetic.
This means
that my first brain is digestive. I was not first cerebralized,
I was first
enteric, I was first digestive. Don’t
forget the five major phases.
Fertilization, gastrulation, neurulation, metamery, and
delimitation.
On the first day, I have an axis here that aligns between my
two polar bodies.
This axis is very important because it forms the basis of my digestive development.
Every time I have a cellular division or cellular cleavage,
there is an increase in my system.
metabolic. In other words, there is an increase in the cell membrane.
But every time I have that, I experience a slight loss of water.
So every time I have this continuous movement in this phase of development,
this force will cause the appearance of a cavity that we call here the blast
ocoel.
Well, we can see here the first image of your digestive system.
We can say it’s the blueprint of
your yolk sac, which will actually be integrated into your digestive tube.
And we see that this cavity is never centered, it is always off-center.
Why? Because it responds to the totality of polarity.
We see this blastocoel appearing, and we see that the embryo here begins to organize itself.
Not only do I have an organization into micromeres, meaning small cells,
where we see I have a vegetative pole, a
bulged pole, an assimilative pole,
a force, a power,
to seek out
trophic information.
I have a cavity,
which is the blastocoel.
Blastocoel means
blastocoel,
the sky, the germ
of the sky.
At some point, I will seek the sky
that I must
integrate into an inner sky.
That is to say, at first,
my digestive system is completely open to the outside and will
slowly integrate
inside. That's why your digestive tube represents
a quality we call
humus. I have humus in my digestive tube. This
humus can be compared to an intestinal flora.
So the living quality of my intestine...
represents the living quality of my terroir in which I am
nourished.
I am first outside, and the sky, in Chinese medicine we talk about this,
I
reintegrate this inside.
The establishment of the yolk cavity and the external coelom.
I am integrated into my uterine lining.
I have here a tissue called trophoblast, this dark layer,
this is another blast cell.
This is an amniotic cavity.
This means I am forming in my developmental phase
between liquid layers.
I am surrounded by liquids.
I develop within these liquids.
Between the two, I have a tissue that overlooks my primitive coelomic cavity.
This will be my digestive system.
I have cells that watch over my amniotic cavity.
This will be my ectodermal, cerebral tissue.
You must understand that this is a process.
growth organized by support points through
differential growth
rates to now understand the establishment of my yolk cavity
and my external coelom, the part that is peripheral
here for the
dark layer is placed in a trophic bath. This layer
here, as it is in the uterus, is the first
layer that receives the nutritional information, so if I eat faster I
grow faster but
since the peripheral layer here grows very very quickly, I have a tearing
between my layer
peripheral and my central layer, this tearing will create a layer of cells that
we call the
Heuser membrane which keeps in contact what we call a
cavity here, and I have the speed here
And it will give what we call a reticulum or mesodermal, extra
-embryonic.
And this reticulum will grow in relation to my periphery.
Here, we see at some point that it tears here.
And this tearing will cause me to transition from a tissue that
we call the blastocoel
to a tissue that we now call the yolk cavity and the external coelom,
to another cavity.
It is in this tissue.
this phase that I will appear under a primitive embryonic pedicle, organized.
It was already there at the moment when I have my extra
-primitive embryonic pedicle, at the
time of the integration of the primitive embryo, at the time of implantation, which is the
first
contact with the mother, not yet organized.
And it is this phase that will organize a form of S within my very
embryonic bud.
And here, there is a point.
of support very important that we have seen, not only do I have an organization of a pedicle
and not only
do I have a support point between a dome of expansion and a dome of compression within
my tissue
which is the blueprint for establishing an axial process of my embryo. This means
that this phase here will lead us to this notochordal phase, a
form of S, and this
form of S will lead to a movement
which is also involved by what we call a permeation field,
a field of infusion and a permeation field
that organizes the amniotic sac toward the front and the yolk sac toward the back
and gives this particular shape to my embryo with this S shape.
And if I have a support point, the cells that are in the convergent part
will grow faster than the cells that are in the convex part,
concave with a support point here that is a fixed point, it's called how this point
future base of the skull we call point 0, it's the blueprint of what is called the craniosacral axis
primitive means that I will find myself with a specific movement organized here
by acid or basic fields
We have two types of different pH in my amniotic or yolk cavity,
with what we call a neuro-enteric canal reorganizing my metabolic plan,
but at the same time, the embryo begins to take its shape here,
with this axial process that develops,
with synchronous phenomena,
making that not only at this level,
I have the whole rupture of my asymmetry,
but I have a very important axial process developing.
This axial process...
here, notochordal, is the basis of the overall development of
my embryo.
And we saw that this axial process was an organizing center for the entirety of my embryo,
that it was organized with a support point we called the base of the skull and the notochordal axis,
up to my sacrum, and that between the two, I would find myself on an umbilical plane.
So we could almost say that I develop between my navel and my
navel.
base of the skull. My heart that will give my diaphragm and my liver. There is an
intelligence in my development. It’s as if we were saying it was
an invagination. But if we see it
in the whole and in growth, it’s
an evagination. What does it change? It changes my support point. If it
were an
invagination, it would be my sacrum that would be the fixed point.
But ultimately, the sacrum becomes a mobile fulcrum like my sternum.
So my real support point is to bring my sacrum back to its
embryonic fulcrum
to restore its primary function of reorganization.
Because at that moment, I have different functions that will develop.
I have superpositions.
Not only do I have an axial process, so truly a primitive craniosacral axis,
But at the same time, I have a rupture of symmetry.
That is to say that I have a nodal flux that changes the molecular aspect of my embryo
on an electrical plane, which makes that I have morphogenetic particles that will develop alongside.
And so, in this movement, I have all the genomic organization developing.
So, if I restore an embryonic fulcrum, the body knows how to reorganize itself.
First, the ombrine.
And then, the basilar pheno.
Then, the heart.
then the diaphragm, then the liver, then the adrenal glands, then the gonadal structures.
In fact, what is my sacrum?
But it is the base of the skull.
I cannot separate them.
This level here is my embryonic fulcrum.
Why? Because at that moment,
the future base of the skull and the sacrum become one.
This is...
a functional unit, in fact. It needs to be understood in its function. I
have a flat base tissue,
throughout this developmental movement, there is a cavity that develops
toward the front like this,
and this yolk sac which develops toward the back. But also intrinsic qualities,
which means I transition from an S-shaped system. The organized cells
with respect to my dome facing forward,
will develop much faster than the cells that are in the back.
Which means that overall,
if I now look just at the glass in its totality,
in growth, I notice this,
that I have a point of no overall growth.
There will be this development of this base.
And then, what do I have?
I have a support point called the future base.
skull that is to say it is the tip of my notochord; on either side, I
have the paraxial cartilage,
the hypophysial cartilage, and what will become of the
hypophysial cartilage and the paraxial cartilage, the
occipital system and the sphenoidal system that
is organized with a point
of support that is a global support point, what we call a support point
A fixed, relative point, if you will, that becomes,
gradually, the area where what we call will develop
the occipito-sphenoidal system, here, that
is the result of this developmental movement.
You see, when I take my sacrum here, it’s what we did, I connect to its embryonic fulcrum,
that is to say I connect, ultimately, to...
to its point, what I call the image
of the Tao, you see.
Here, I have a point, here,
where the tissue here is in hyperactivity,
in hypoactivity, so I have
a support point
between two movements, what
I call the pre-morphogenetic force,
which has not yet taken on form, structure,
but which contains its potential,
and already at this level
on a sacral and occipital plane.
Once I have this support point, the body knows what it has to do since it has its organizational plan.
It's one of the first things it does in its form.
This form gives this axis.
I take my sacrum, and here I have a notochordal axis that it has, primitive.
Then there will be a regression of the structure, but not of my function.
My function is always there because it is primitive.
It organizes a structure at the occipital level.
Sometimes there are people who have deviations. They have false fulcrums. They
have false support points.
That’s why I say it is necessary to learn to work with health. Because
that is health.
It is always there. At first, it’s a field, dense, and
then in growth, it will regress.
This means that my notochord, what is the vestige of my notochord? It’s my pulpy nucleus.
Okay, so a kind of regression in the tissue, but the axis is given by
this moment, we will
see that this is what we call the median line, three median lines, we call
the notochordal median line, the neural median line, and the median line that we studied
last time, the anterior digestive median line. We can also see what we call
the
linea alba, that’s called the white line in a pregnant woman
we still see this line appearing, which is the closure on the testicles.
We see the scrotum in women; we still see the line clearly.
If you look at the palate, you see all these axes.
Bruno Cicli adds a fourth, which is an electric field,
whose vital point will be found at the level of the hara.
More precisely, because it is still umbilical,
but if we look, there is a vascular vestige
that will be found, what we call a diverticulum,
organized by my...
omphalo-mesenteric plan, that is to say, the superior mesenteric artery.
Not only do I have a rupture of my asymmetry, but during this moment, I have also established
my third tissue, what we call pure mesodermal tissue.
I have my notochordal axis, I have the axis, what we call the primitive line,
and the
first impulse of the movement of my original tissue.
Epithelial is a tissue that will first organize my endoderm
so this means
that my ectoderm or what I call the primitive epiblast of
ectodermal type
will already influence by this primitive line and by my
axial process my digestive system in its organization, then
after I'm going to
have my mesoderm, which is primarily it’s an electric field.
We all come from one cell. And we all come from what type of cell? We all come from
an epithelial cell. Not mesodermic. It’s a developmental movement.
Just for the liver. But I cannot separate it from its context. I have a flexion movement
of my embryo. The flexion movement of my embryo will bring the heart to
its place.
It will create a pressure.
on the upper yolk sac, the upper part.
It will integrate cells that are beyond my precordial plate
to form a space that will delimit the cardiac part from
the peritoneal part.
And what will this delimitation create?
It will create what we call the primitive diaphragm, the transverse septum.
The flow of information keeps arriving.
And this time,
it arrives in a different compartment.
So the trophic information flow, the torrent of water arriving,
will begin to congest under the diaphragm.
And this congestion space, on a mesodermic level,
in relation to the endodermic level, will create a first sketch called the liver.
But the embryo has grown.
And at a certain point, my liver, through modifying vascular fields,
will grow to the right. It will not turn to the
right.
It will grow to the right. And these are embryonic movements.
I can develop that way, you see.
I have the space, as the heart, at a certain moment, we say it goes to the left.
No, it can develop over there. It grows over there.
So it means that my embryonic movements are movements of development
in the growth phase. It’s the inner forces of
expansion. It’s the arteries,
it’s the vascular movements that decide. We organize around your fluidic field.
And during what does your fluidic field organize? Your electric field. And where does it come from
?
Ultimately from the void. So ultimately I organize myself in chaos. It’s there that this notochordal
will
give the impulse for the neural plate.
I have a neural tissue here above, like this,
all is well.
And then suddenly, there’s a notochordal axis that arrives below.
A well-placed thing.
There are metabolic movements.
Imagine that the ceiling here is my neural plate.
And here, I have my notochord.
In the void here, like this, that’s there.
The cells that are right there are slowed down in their growth.
They are slowed.
I have here the primitive ectoderm.
I have my notochord
that has information
here, with a slowing down
this time, again, it is a matter of growth speeds
differentials, it’s the same
algorithm, which makes the zone
that is here, I do not grow at the same speed
but here,
I begin to form what we call a groove
you see
and this groove here, like this
changes the compartment
here. And what will it change? It will change a vascular system.
That is to say
that I have a vascular trajectory that is organizing. And I return to my initial algorithm.
The mesodermic tissue, the internal tissue, does not grow at the same speed
and becomes a driver because it brings trophic information, it nourishes the cells. But
the
tube does not grow at the same speed. It slows down.
Above, like I’m eating a lot, I’m becoming obese.
I develop and I coil.
And this is how the process of
If I take a primitive vascular field
here,
and I put it behind my embryo here, which is like this, let’s say, my
neural tube,
this is what happens.
growth occurs like this with a
coiling ultimately around my cardiac zone that
pushes
on the upper yolk sac of my sac, which is
going to create the transverse septum
here, the continuous flow of information arriving here which we manage
so we can say that the cerebralization
that leads to the cardialization, which leads to the diaphragm formation, which leads to
hepatization.
After that, there will be a pulmonary space, so there is a pneumatisation,
which will open a space between the posterior part and
the liver, which will create the adrenalization.
To have the organization and the final establishment of my gonads, I need my adrenal glands.
And my kidneys.
So we see here that the cord initially fades.
of the neuro-hypophyseal bud at the floor of the diencephalon,
the future base of the skull.
It’s the developmental movement of the notochordal process
that will allow the future development
of my skull base and my sacrum.
Whereas up to the cloacal membrane,
future space for sacral development.
It’s a notochord that will be placed there,
which just happens to be at the tip of the Douglas cul-de-sac.
the terminal part of my peritoneum.
Here we see, you see, all the primitive notochordal axis
with my skull base and my sacrum.
We see here, you see, my notochord
up to the level of my skull base.
We see again here my notochordal process
up to my skull base.
You see, the tip of what we call the Douglas cul-de-sac,
the terminal part,
with my notochord, the bending of the embryo well
understand this fluidic dynamic. We see clearly
here the coiling of the embryo development, elongation, growth
but look closely
as it becomes a support point; my vascular system, you see the approximation of my tubes
endocardial here because they do not grow at the same speed. In fact, the error in this drawing is that we
close above my
neural tube, I have the integration of the pharyngeal intestine, for example, in the caudal part
and at the same time, I have the closure of my neural tube. So the first 28th day, I
have
the integration of my external coelom into an internal coelom and I have the integration of
my neural tube into an internal neural tube. This means that for the first time
I have a support point on a level of the cerebrospinal fluid that I have integrated
into
its first personality.
I depart from my embryonic pedicle and I return to
my embryonic pedicle.
I make the movement for me of Umaï Rémaï.
You found it.
Maybe it was there in its function; here it becomes its structure.
So what’s important to conceive is that I coil around
my vascular plan.
That’s why it’s always necessary to bring the fluids toward the center.
to have in the development of my circulatory system, that ultimately
it goes from
the periphery to the center. I must come together.
I dive into the tissue water. I dive into my
tissue. I swim a little at first. When I find a movement, I
find a support point, a point
of balance. I fix. Then, analyze the tissue.
And there you enter into the history of Becker's tissue, there you enter into the memory.
But you must touch the tissue where it wants to be recognized, and not where you want
to recognize it.
First thing, I listen to its movement; once I find its fulcrum, its balance point,
and there I enter into its history, at a certain point, I pass, I enter, I merge,
and the tissue will give you an image,
a word that may come from afar, huh, what is it?
either on an embryonic point or even, for some, have
the transgenerational capacity.